Software Engineer

An enthusiastic Software Engineer with 2+ years of experience. Proficient in **HTML5**, **CSS3**, **JavaScript**, **ECMAScript**, **React**, **C#**, and **Unity** game engine. Experienced with React Native, Redux, Bootstrap, RESTful APIs, asynchronous request handling, TypeScript, Figma, Jenkins, WordPress, Jira, agile methodology, and version control systems such as Git and Perforce. Knowledgeable in databases like SQL and GraphQL, data modelling, and server-side programming languages and frameworks like PHP and Laravel. Good understanding of responsive design principles, cross-browser compatibility, and UX/UI design principles. Strong communication and teamwork skills, ability to understand business requirements, and problem-solving skills, enhanced by a background in Hospitality and Business. A volunteer Co-host/Mentor of <u>Vancouver.dev</u> & <u>CS Dojo Vancouver</u> communities, and a member of the LGBT community.

Check out my Portfolio & Projects, code base, and blogs. Note that this website is coded only in pure HTML, CSS, and JavaScript without using any libraries or frameworks, and deployed to Vercel.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Software Developer
PIP Empire | Remote, Canada

Mar 2024 - Present

- Collaborate effectively in cross-functional teams to finalize the UX/UI design and technical requirements.
- Develop new user-facing features and reusable components with React.js, NextJS, and Tailwind.
- Complete the technical documentation with the code progress.
- Participate in code reviews and debugging to maintain code quality and share knowledge with the team.

# **Frontend Software Engineer**

Feb 2024 - Present

GoodBot (Volunteer) | Remote, Canada

- · Implement an input system to save user data in the database via API calls using React and NextJS.
- Collaborate with backend developers to integrate APIs and test software to ensure responsiveness and efficiency.
- Assist the UX/UI design team in redesigning an MVP web application.

#### **Associate Software Engineer**

May 2021 - Aug 2023

East Side Games Studio | Remote, Canada

- Learned and efficiently utilized new technologies and tools for 5 different projects.
- Improved performance of existing components, such as the User's ID Copy-to-Clipboard feature and dialog popup calling frequency cooldown.
- Engaged in pair programming to determine the architecture of a new Unity project, and developed the UI of the "Delete Account" feature based on UX/UI design mock-ups.
- Safely integrated new technologies like SonarCloud continuous integration/continuous deployment (CI/CD) pipelines, updated dependencies, and replaced SDKs and third-party libraries.
- Removed unwanted components from the UI, and troubleshot and debugged front-end issues including missing animations, audio reset bugs, and image overlaps.
- Initiated research and conducted usability and playtesting to identify the potential areas for player retention improvement. Collected and condensed the data and provided the documentation to the CEO.

#### Frontend (Mobile) Developer

Jan 2022 - Sep 2022

iContribute (Volunteer) | Remote, Canada

• Implemented the new features' UI code using Bootstrap, and the in-house CSS rules for their mobile app.

### **EDUCATION**

## **British Columbia Institute of Technology (BCIT)**

2019 - 2021

Applied Web Development - Associate Certificate

# **European University of Yerevan**

International Economics Relations (International Business) - Master's Degree

### **Bonyad University of Applied Science**

Hospitality & Hotel Management - Non-Continues Bachelor's degree